<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[@wrought]]></title>
  <link href="http://existenceproof.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://existenceproof.net"/>
  <updated>2014-08-24T03:16:53.959Z</updated>
  <id>http://existenceproof.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Senate]]></name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo">Hexo</generator>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step Beyond Pretense for a Moment]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/step-beyond-pretense-for-a-moment/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/step-beyond-pretense-for-a-moment/</id>
    <published>2014-08-23T11:56:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-24T03:12:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first thing you must do, no alternative, is to remember (not merely believe, but to recall something utterly meaningful, which rests deep within your thoughts and experiences), you must remember that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>the world is not as it may seem</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You learned this lesson very young, making assumptions about the world that quickly worked themselves out of utility, out of fashion, out of mind.</p>
<p>Please, soak in this notion, in the impossibility of total understanding, seeing, knowing.</p>
<p>How <em>easy</em> is it to <strong>forget</strong> that at any given moment, perhaps, someone is <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/pull+the+wool+over+someone&#39;s+eyes" target="_blank">pulling the wool over your eyes</a>? How easy is it to accept (without justification) that the world as we know it is the “only way it can be”? We are strongly biased. We assume the current state of affairs offers the only possibility for life, society, everything. We are all susceptible to such thinking, but we know well the feeling of emptiness it brings.</p>
<p>We know the “truth” is that each of us, individually, live restricted and exploited lives; lives disrupted in both practical and psychological senses. We often deny ourselves and each other the liberty of even <em>imagining</em> new aspects of the world, those things yet to be seen. We spend much time repeating viscious cycles and promoting the status quo or dominant culture, at times in that “whatever&#39;s easiest” mentality.</p>
<p>Although it is practically impossible to predict the future, we still live our day-to-day lives as though most of everything exists somewhere above our heads, pre-determined, immutable, out of our control, as though there is some  <em>natural</em> order. What a dangerous, false thought.</p>
<p>It is integral to set ourselves free, one by one, to accept there is no singular truth, and certainly no “correct” universe. Nor is the universe immutable&mdash;stuck in its current state, without alternatives.</p>
<p>Our reality is multiplicitous and duplicitous. Our reality consists of many, overlapping worlds. And these worlds are not always truthful. We continuously construct our own memories, knowledge, life. Through social dimensions we constitute shared realities&mdash;sometimes (tragically) through domination, yet other times through consent, or something in between.</p>
<p>People, on the whole, are more creative than we often give credit; just imagine what creative potential we deny or ignore! Instead, we have the ability to accept or support one another in our creativity.</p>
<p>It is time to embrace, celebrate this basic understanding of truth and the world. From it so much flows, and so interesting life then becomes.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/perspective/" term="perspective"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/culture/" term="culture"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/view/" term="view"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/philosophy/" term="philosophy"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/how-to/" term="how-to"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/guide/" term="guide"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/steps/" term="steps"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/process/" term="process"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/important/" term="important"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/politics/" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/future/" term="future"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/vision/" term="vision"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/life/" term="life"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bring Your OS With You]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/bring-your-os-with-you/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/bring-your-os-with-you/</id>
    <published>2014-08-15T20:40:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T23:16:42.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I support and celebrate operating systems based on Linux, well, because there are not many better options. ;) On the other hand, I also believe that community-supported tools and systems are worth our participation and involvement, because for what we all put in, we each, and collectively, get much more out. Simple as that.</p>
<p>Right now I run <a href="http://crunchbang.com/" target="_blank">CrunchBang</a>, a snappy, simplified, developer-conscious flavor of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debian" target="_blank">Debian</a>, notably running the OpenBox window manager rather than something heftier like GNOME.</p>
<p>Since installing CrunchBang, I have come to appreciate its simplicity so much that I have wanted to continue using it, with all of my alterations, even as I upgrade my laptop. In this post, I outline a strategy to simplify management of your Linux system based on my experience so far with my operating system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bring your OS with you</p>
</blockquote>
<ol>
<li>Pick an operating system. (For me at the moment, it&#39;s CrunchBang)<ol>
<li>Download an <code>.iso</code> (image) file</li>
<li>Use <code>unetbootin</code> or <code>dd</code> (<a href="http://linuxcommand.org/man_pages/dd1.html" target="_blank">details</a>) to copy the image to a usb drive<ol>
<li>For using <code>dd</code>, find out the device names of your disks with <code>dmesg | grep sd</code>, which allows you to see details about drives and when they are connected.</li>
<li>Pick the right locations and fire <strong>[WARNING, MAY DESTROY STUFF]</strong>:<br> <code>dd if=/home/username/downloads/linux-foo-bar-0.1.iso of=/dev/sdBBB</code></li>
<li>Once finished, you can reboot, select the flash drive as the boot disk (usually change some settings in BIOS and then use some key like F12 to select boot device from a list)</li>
<li>Follow your OS&#39;s installation instructions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Exact backup to empty drive with <code>dd</code><ol>
<li>Boot from a live OS (live disk, like CD or usb drive with linux on it)</li>
<li>Again, find the correct device names of disks first</li>
<li>This time copy from your computer&#39;s disk instead of an image to some backup file <strong>[WARNING, MAY DESTROY STUFF]</strong>:<br> <code>dd if=/dev/sdAAA of=/dev/sdBBB</code></li>
<li>To recover a <em>borked</em> system, you can always copy in the other direction to restore <strong>[WARNING, MAY DESTROY STUFF]</strong>:<br> <code>dd if=/dev/sdBBB of=/dev/sdAAA</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Backup with <code>horcrux</code> on top of <code>duplicity</code> (<a href="http://chrispoole.com/project/horcrux/" target="_blank">details</a>)<ol>
<li>This is for more magic, like multiple restoration points, partial backups, and most importantly, backing up to multiple locations in case of multiple failures</li>
<li><code>horcrux</code> is pretty much a <code>bash</code> script for <code>duplicity</code>, so read it and <code>man duplicity</code>!</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Store <em>special</em> files with <code>tomb</code> (<a href="https://www.dyne.org/software/tomb/" target="_blank">details</a>)<ol>
<li>A fun and tiny way to bury bits on your disk, excellent alternative to full-disk encryption schemes</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Migrate to new devices with <code>dd</code> and <code>lvm</code><ol>
<li>When it&#39;s time to upgrade or replace your computer, you can carry everything with you. There is only one important question:<ol>
<li>Is the destination hard drive bigger or smaller than my current one?<ol>
<li>Either way you will have to resize the <em>physical volume</em> and <em>logical volumes</em> in question, but if the destination drive is bigger, than you can copy now and resize later ;)<ol>
<li>Resizing un-encrypted partitions can be as easy as running <code>gparted</code>, <code>parted</code>, <code>fdisk</code>, or simply with <code>lvm</code> commands</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>However, encrypted partitions are not as easy to manage. See notes below for resizing encrypted partitions:</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Pro-tip:</em> Check the progress of <code>dd</code> with <code>sudo kill -USR1 `pidof dd` </code></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Enlarging LUKS Encryption over LVM</h3>
<p>These days, it‘s easy to implement full-disk encryption at the time of your operating system’s installation. Further, it&#39;s usually recommended to use LVM to manage your disks, even on a personal computer. <code>lvm</code> creates a layer of abstraction on top of typical partitions, which can make some forms of disk management much easier or less risky. If you installed a recent distribution of linux based on Debian, and installed fill-disk encryption it is likely you are using LUKS over LVM. </p>
<p>For debian-based systems, this guide called <a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/ResizeEncryptedPartitions" target="_blank">Resize Encrypted Partitions</a> should be close to what you need, with some noteworthy updates:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Step 1.</strong> When creating a new partition “next to and to the left of (after) your crypt”, don&#39;t let this language confuse you. You want the encrypted partition to have a new partition immediately following it so that you may use <code>fdisk</code> to overwrite this new partition by expanding the encrypted partition over the new partition. This should help make more sense of the situation. It&#39;s likely that you have <code>/dev/sda1</code> with <code>/boot</code> on it and <code>/dev/sda2</code> as an extended partition that contains your encrypted partition (something like <code>/dev/sda5</code> maybe, depending on how many partitions you made at installation and later with LVM). This is why it is likely that creating another Linux partition inside of the <code>/dev/sda2</code> extended partition would likely use the name <code>/dev/sda6</code> as the instructions note. If you view this in <code>gparted</code> you would see <code>/dev/sda2</code> wrapped around the encrypted <code>/dev/sda5</code> as well as around the following new partition <code>/dev/sda6</code>, ending the wrapper.</li>
<li><strong>Step 2.</strong> Don&#39;t bother with <code>/dev/urandom</code> it takes forever, just use <code>/dev/zero</code> or if you prefer, you can use <code>shred</code> instead of <code>dd</code> with the <code>--iterations</code> flag as such: <code>sudo shred --iterations=1 /dev/sda6</code></li>
<li><strong>Step 3.</strong> This is a very confusing reference. You are instructed to use <code>fdisk</code> in the same process as it is used for shrinking partitions in the instructions preceeding these (above). However, there are superfluous warnings, commands, and instructions that make it difficult to implement here. The important concept to note, in my opinion, is simply that you are using fdisk to expand your encrypted partition over the new, adjacent partition. This means you should use <code>fdisk /dev/sda</code> to <code>d</code> delete partitions <code>6</code>, <code>5</code> and <code>2</code>, then <code>n</code> re-create them as partitions <code>2</code> (<code>e</code> expanded) and <code>5</code> (<code>l</code> logical) such that (by default) <code>/dev/sda5</code> expands over the blocks previously partitioned for <code>/dev/sda6</code>. Check with <code>p</code> and when you are satisfied, <code>w</code> write to the disk.</li>
<li>After <strong>Step 8.</strong> If you are troubleshooting the process, to deactivate your LVM, use <code>sudo vgchange -an</code></li>
<li><strong>Step 11.</strong> Repeat as necessary for each <em>logical volume</em> you wish to resize (e.g. <code>root</code>, <code>swap</code>, and <code>home</code>)</li>
<li><strong>Step 12.</strong> You won&#39;t be able to resize the filesystem for swap. If you do resize a swap volume, when you reboot and complete the resizing successfully, simply use <code>mkswap</code> appropriately such as:<br> <code>sudo swapoff</code><br> <code>sudo mkswap /dev/crypt1/swap_1</code><br> <code>sudo swapon</code></li>
</ol>
<h2>The Future</h2>
<p>Maybe in the future I will switch to ArchLinux to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rolling_release/" target="_blank">avoid major upgrade headaches</a>, get on board with the new future-of-linux features, and benefit from a great community with lots of documentation..</p>
<p>In fact, I&#39;m downloading Arch right now… ;)</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/operating system/" term="operating system"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/os/" term="os"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/linux/" term="linux"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/crunchbang/" term="crunchbang"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/philosophy/" term="philosophy"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/style/" term="style"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/tools/" term="tools"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Rule to Guide Them All]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/one_rule_to_guide_them_all/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/one_rule_to_guide_them_all/</id>
    <published>2014-07-20T17:52:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-21T08:55:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Food must be shared.” &mdash; <a href="https://kesselberg.info" target="_blank">Kesselberg</a> (Community)</p>
<p>“Be excellent to each other.” &mdash; <a href="https://noisebridge.net" target="_blank">Noisebridge</a> (Hackerspace)</p>
<p>“Don&#39;t be evil.” &mdash; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google" target="_blank">Google</a> (Company)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How do we socially organize? How do we share our most basic principles, morals, values? What does it mean when we simplify, when we search for or even implement essentialized notions as the baseline for a community&#39;s standards?</p>
<p>Three examples have come to mind of late and instigate these questions for me. I do not have the answers, but it creates an alluring pursuit.</p>
<h2>Kesselberg (Berlin)</h2>
<p>First, Kesselberg is an unrestricted, autonomous, intentional community outside of Berlin, Germany. The community has quite a strong core who have been living in their discrete location for some time. On the other hand, the place is truly open to anyone who wants to come there, and thus some people come who are less intentional about their stay with respect to the others, but are allowed nonetheless. A dynamic exists between these groups, and I cannot say where it stands at the moment, though I am attempting to investige further. Ultimately, there is only one rule. If you have food, you need to share it. This is a clever concept, focusing on commoning a basic human need and resource, as well as identifying a mode for social exchange around the hearth, bowl, hand, fire, etc. Its implications prove interesting at the very least.</p>
<h2>Noisebridge (San Francisco)</h2>
<p>Another community, Noisebridge, in the mission district of San Francisco, also has just one rule. Quoting Keanu Reeves in <strong>Bill and Ted&#39;s Excellent Adventure</strong>. Reeves plays a Southern Californian teenager who travels in time in order to learn history, finish his final project for his history class,  and graduate from high school. If he fails, in the future, he won&#39;t later co-create a peaceful society guided by the music and philosophy of his excellent rock-and-roll band. </p>
<p>Travelling to this future society, Reeve&#39;s character learns from their leaders that his future self has taught the planet about world peace. He is prompted to share some wisdom. He takes a moment, gets all poetic on us, and states, “Be excellent to each other.” Nothing more appropriate for culture-jamming hackers to adopt as their basic and altruistic motto for moral guidance.</p>
<p>However, “Be excellent to each other” is not perfect. In the Noisebridge community, there has been much ambiguity around this notion and phrasing. Further, to emphasize being excellent has suggested to some that therefore some attitude, behaviors, and practices are <strong>“un-excellent”</strong> and should therefore be identified, prevented, or otherwise opposed in the spirit of being “excellent” instead. On the other hand, the hacker community has memetically spread this rule around the world where it has a place and application in many other communities. It is certainly imperfect, but it has legs, which is worth a ponder…</p>
<h2>Google</h2>
<p>Finally, there is one dangerously simplistic phrase, for which there is certainly ample debate already. Google‘s “Don’t be evil” has the opposite <em>problem</em> as being “excellent” has for Noisebridge. Why state this principle in the negative? Why should being “evil” be avoided? We shouldn&#39;t we “be good” or some similar positive equivalent? In some way, we see the practice of this essential concept at work as Google grows in its wealth and power. Will Google become evil? Is Google evil in some ways already? What is evil? What are the good things that Google does? Can they be compared to the evil, or is evil absolute and represent a fundamental failure?</p>
<h2>In sum…</h2>
<p>To me, I am most impressed by Kesselberg‘s statement because (unlike the other two above), it has a clear but unviable opposite. To not share one’s food is unambiguous. In some way keeping, food to one‘s self (in most cases) would lean toward self-interest and away from commons-building. If the priority of the community is to share one’s food if one has food, then greater than self-evidence, this community has a reasonable request for which the opposite can be easily understood, as it is fairly undebatable (at least in construction). I think this may be an indicator of what can make a very valuable basis of a moral system.</p>
<p>Additionally, Kesselberg‘s food sharing notion converges on one of a person’s most basic needs, functions, and elements of day-to-day life. The sharing of food creates the possibility and potential for further interaction and engagement. It is such sharing that brings people together, where other aspects of culture may emerge and flourish. Time to listen, to understand, to express, be creative, to relax, and to grow, bonding with others.</p>
<h2>In Math…</h2>
<p>In the practice of mathematics, an informal (non-binding) principle is the concept of <strong>elegance</strong>. Simply put, elegance emphasizes (even prioritizes) simplicity. If something can be said as one shorter statement, rather than two, then do it! It&#39;s of course not universal, and there are lots of counter examples, as you might imagine. Further, elegance may very well be anthropocentric; do the context and constraints of being a human predispose or bias us away from complexity in our models? I believe this certainly can be the case, and therefore we should be aware of such bias.</p>
<p>From a logical stand-point, non-trivial but minimal systems that demonstrate elegance can be illustrative, powerful (theoretically), and even practical. For instance, consider in propositional logic, the functionally complete formal system constructed from a single operator: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_NAND" target="_blank">Nand or “not and”</a>. This system allows the construction of all the commonly sensical equivalents of logic (‘and’, ‘or’, ‘implies’, ‘not’, etc) in a more abstract way (complex in length, simple in basis). On top of it all, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NAND_logic" target="_blank">logical Nand</a> is the operation implemented in the Nand gate, the tool by which computational machines may function!</p>
<p>These simple rules or statements used by the communities listed above make me think about such mathematical elegance, in a heuristical and poetic sense.</p>
<p>&lt;/end&gt;</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/rules/" term="rules"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/principles/" term="principles"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/ideology/" term="ideology"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/morality/" term="morality"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/theory/" term="theory"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/community/" term="community"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/communities/" term="communities"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/creative communities/" term="creative communities"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackers/" term="hackers"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hacker ethic/" term="hacker ethic"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hacker culture/" term="hacker culture"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/culture/" term="culture"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/guidance/" term="guidance"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/noisebridge/" term="noisebridge"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/berlin/" term="berlin"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/kesselberg/" term="kesselberg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Villagecraft Update and New Workshop on Starting A Hackerspace]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/villagecraft-update-and-new-workshop-on-starting-a-hackerspace/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/villagecraft-update-and-new-workshop-on-starting-a-hackerspace/</id>
    <published>2014-06-11T02:30:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-11T23:44:43.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just met up with Hayley from <a href="http://villagecraft.org/" target="_blank">Villagecraft.org</a> at sudo room. Got some updates about the progress of their project, including some exciting patterns from their user base and general solidarity across creative/learning community life!</p>
<p>Zero<sup>th</sup>, they&#39;re hosting a Dinner Party this Thursday June 12th at 6pm, register on villagecraft itself to join.</p>
<p>First, they&#39;re going <em>open source</em>, which means they&#39;ll finally be publishing their source code online, opening up the prospect of review, contribution, and creativity with the very platform that runs the villagecraft website. They support a community of hosts and attendees sharing knowledge at workshop-style events in the east bay area. This is certainly a project <a href="https://lists.sudoroom.org/" target="_blank">sudoers</a> will be interested in examining more closely.</p>
<p>Second, they have a <strong>plan</strong> ;). Meaning, they&#39;ve got a list of features <em>and</em> a list of bugs that they plan to get through to truly improve the villagecraft experience. Hayley spends a lot of time in the field, doing manual coordination, listening, and problem-solving. The results of her lessons she shares back to the rest of the team, most of whom write the bulk of the villagecraft software.</p>
<p>Third, and finally, the future is uncertain! New folks are getting on board to write software, and the organic user community is growing in interesting and strange ways (more on that below). There are open questions, big opportunities, and a clear need to grow wider (and not necessarily spend too much time going so deep). Hayley reached out on this particular accord, hoping to include more participation from hackerspace, techie, hardware/software/wetware communities. It seems to me the opportunity to cross sudo room‘s events and villagecraft’s community platform is certainly real, and very exciting.</p>
<p>As for these user patterns. Two things Hayley shared are:<br>1. The villagecraft user base is growing inter-connected as an organic community.<br>2. Some of their users take several workshops across domains, rather than focus on individual domains.</p>
<p>These patterns seem to imply that the time to widen and grow the community is nigh. Further, the intuitive notion that users will pursue learning experiences based on the domain-specificity of their interests may very well be untrue thusfar!</p>
<p>Lastly, Hayley, Jeremy, and I shared some of our interests and experiences working in creative communities, using consensus, using safe space, positioning do-ocracy over bureaucracy, celebrating good-faith collaboration, and confronting bad-faith participants. As a result of our discussion, looks like I&#39;ll be hosting a workshop on <a href="http://villagecraft.org/w/3c71912c-starting-a-hackerspace" target="_blank">Starting a Hackerspace</a>, based on the <a href="https://sudoroom.org/" target="_blank">sudo room</a> experience, conversations with folks starting hackerspaces locally as well as remotely, and my recent post on an off-the-cuff protocol: <a href="http://existenceproof.net/zero-to-hackerspace-in-eight-steps/">8 steps to start a hackerspace</a>. Additionally, Jeremy will be hosting one on <em>Consensus Process</em>, which we all agreed is much needed and even long-overdue.</p>
<p>Very exciting ;).</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/villagecraft/" term="villagecraft"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/workshops/" term="workshops"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/creative communities/" term="creative communities"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/learning/" term="learning"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/teaching/" term="teaching"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/facilitatoin/" term="facilitatoin"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/methodologies/" term="methodologies"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/theory/" term="theory"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/basics/" term="basics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero to Hackerspace in Eight Steps]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/zero-to-hackerspace-in-eight-steps/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/zero-to-hackerspace-in-eight-steps/</id>
    <published>2014-06-09T23:14:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-09T23:46:50.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have begun to discuss with some local folks about a nascent hackerspace in the east bay area. More details on that forthcoming. Reviewing some of our messages about this, I found an interesting little ditty. I wrote it in a stream of consciousness after an in-person meeting to try to quickly simplify my own mental model of starting a hackerspace.</p>
<h2>Eight Steps to Hackerspace</h2>
<p>The overall process I find successful for hackerspaces is:</p>
<ol>
<li>Open up a dialog by meeting regularly, hosting an email list (maybe also a website, wiki, and irc channel).</li>
<li>Invite potential members/participants and stakeholders, challenge yourself to be accessible to a wider community, strive for equity and parity.</li>
<li>Seek to remain transparent, mutually accountable, and to build stakeholdership and ownership of new members/participants.</li>
<li>Set an agenda for each meeting beforehand. Give each item a time limit, adjusting as necessary. Designate a facilitator and note-taker, rotating as necessary (even mid-meeting). Always post the notes afterwards (on email list, wiki, etc). Switch roles, trade off and build comfort, skill, experience collaborating together.</li>
<li>Share your individual visions. Collaborate to form a shared vision, based on consent. Write it down. Improve it.</li>
<li>Collectively determine the goals that will allow you to accomplish concrete steps toward that shared vision.</li>
<li>Value safe space <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safe-space" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safe-space</a></li>
<li>Hack the planet.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Reflection</h2>
<p>Oddly enough, this has little to do with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_ethic/" target="_blank">hacking</a> per se! It has more to do with ensuring that your community is best able to express itself in an air of empathy, excitement, and collaboration. It is very easy to close up, to act more like a club, or to lose track of how to remain open, accessible, and fair. It is difficult, however, to remain diligent, awake, and improve as you grow and create your hackerspace. Ultimately, the details of what <em>kind</em> of hacking you do, and what sort of <em>arrangement</em> you make of your space will be important, but not nearly as important as dreaming, together, along with your community, and ensuring that you share portions of these dreams, sufficient to know what directions to go.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/step-by-step/" term="step-by-step"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/process/" term="process"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/protocol/" term="protocol"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/dialog/" term="dialog"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/consensus/" term="consensus"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/community/" term="community"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/consent/" term="consent"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/vision/" term="vision"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/shared vision/" term="shared vision"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/stakeholdership/" term="stakeholdership"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/equity/" term="equity"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/parity/" term="parity"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/accessibility/" term="accessibility"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/facilitation/" term="facilitation"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/transparency/" term="transparency"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/organizing/" term="organizing"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ABC No Rio]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/abc-no-rio/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/abc-no-rio/</id>
    <published>2014-06-05T22:41:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-05T20:08:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While in town for <a href="http://wikiconferenceusa.org/" target="_blank">WikiConference USA</a> I had the pleasure of spending a bit of extra time in New York City. Some kind souls were generous enough to spend their time with me, showing their spaces, answering questions, and generally mutually sharing our experiences. One such group who opened their doors and obliged an extended conversation is <a href="http://abcnorio.org/" target="_blank">ABC No Rio</a>.</p>
<p>I stopped by the space previously, but no one was around, so I glanced at various (past and present) event postings on flyers and posters around the doors, though I couldn&#39;t make it to any I saw. However, I <em>was</em> able to step inside once I had a chance to schedule a conversation with two long-term volunteers of the space, who also are board members for the 501(c)3 non-profit organization that supports it. This organization exists primarily to keep ABC No Rio&#39;s physical location in community control, coordinate fund-raising for improvements (see notes about <a href="#rebuild">re-build</a> below), and to otherwise support the continued existence of the community. Otherwise, all the function of the space itself is performed by individual volunteers through the various sub-collectives of ABC No Rio, and one non-profit tenant of the building.</p>
<p>Genuinely, ABC is a commons, though one that has seen fluctuating usage and emphases over the years. A group and place that has remained open for 30 years, spanning not only societal eras, but eras all their own. Currently, there are the following collectives in the space:</p>
<ul>
<li>Visual Arts<ul>
<li>Run gallery space at entrance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Music Performances (esp. punk)<ul>
<li>Double gallery as music venue</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Free jazz / improv<ul>
<li>Also use gallery space for performances</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Zine library<ul>
<li>Upstairs half floor</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Dark Room<ul>
<li>Upstairs half floor</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Screenprinting<ul>
<li>Upstairs half floor</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Computer Lab</li>
</ul>
<p>Plus one partner organization leasing space in the basement:</p>
<ul>
<li>Time&#39;s Up (bike workshop)</li>
</ul>
<p><a name="rebuild"></a></p>
<h3>Rebuild</h3>
<p>ABC No Rio owns its current building on Rivington Street in the Lower East Side. It was never in perfect condition, and though it remains functional and accessible, today more than ever it needs attention. Luckily, they are now closer than ever to raising the total ~$7 million to create a brand new building, with a much improved design. They seek connections, donor referrals, and donations.<br><a href="http://abcnorio.org/support/support.html" target="_blank">Contact them to lend your support</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/commons/" term="commons"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/collectives/" term="collectives"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/collective of collectives/" term="collective of collectives"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/new york city/" term="new york city"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/nyc/" term="nyc"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/community spaces/" term="community spaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/fund-raising/" term="fund-raising"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/solidarity/" term="solidarity"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WNDW and Pandoc Conversions]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/wndw-and-pandoc-conversions/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/wndw-and-pandoc-conversions/</id>
    <published>2013-11-09T14:14:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-10T04:31:03.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/tunabananas" target="_blank">tunabananas</a>&#39; adventures in Berlin, I got to pick up a physical copy of <a href="http://wndw.net/" target="_blank">Wireless Networks in the Developing World</a> (WNDW). The book is a complete guide to running wireless networks in a variety of environments, including: background knowledge, regulatory information, technology resources, and community resources from experts in creating and maintaining these networks. It&#39;s an excellent source that I highly recommend to anyone interested in internet, wireless, mesh/local networking, community utilities, and information and communication technologies for development (ict4d).</p>
<p>Further, you are entitled to copy, share, and remix the book since it is released under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" target="_blank">Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike (cc-by-sa) license</a>, so long as your derivative work uses the same license (others can do the same to your version). </p>
<p>I was disappointed to find that the <a href="http://wndw.net/" target="_blank">wndw.net</a> website hosted only PDF and ebook formats, with no source files. With this opportunity and liberty of a permissive license, I did the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Obtained a source copy of the book (<a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/src/WNDW_UsTrade6_master%231.42.odt" target="_blank">.odt</a>) from lead editor <a href="http://networktheworld.org/" target="_blank">Jane Butler</a>.</li>
<li>Used LibreOffice to export an HTML format of the book (<a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/src/WNDW_UsTrade6_master%231.42.html" target="_blank">.html</a>).<ul>
<li>This version is generally fairly good, including MathML for the equations and mathematical statements, but there are some formatting issues, namely in the Glossary.</li>
<li>Also created a simpler copy to clean and improve the HTML (<a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/wndw.html" target="_blank">.html</a>) which includes MathJax JavaScript from the mathjax CDN to format MathML into beautiful mathematical representations. </li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Used <a href="http://johnmacfarlane.net/pandoc/" target="_blank">Pandoc</a> to generate a MarkDown version based on the HTML format (<a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/wndw.md" target="_blank">.md</a>).<ul>
<li>This version is actually really clean, <em>except</em> the math and tables, which need to be reformatted.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Used Pandoc again to generate a MediaWiki format based on the MarkDown format (<a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/wndw.wiki" target="_blank">.wiki</a>).<ul>
<li>Then, I posted the MediaWiki version <a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Wireless_Networking_in_the_Developing_World" target="_blank">on WikiSource</a>, along with a PDF <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:" target="_blank">on Wikimedia Commons</a>.</li>
<li>The MediaWiki version still needs math and images to be added and uploaded respectively.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Community Editing</h2>
<p>Now there&#39;s a few versions, but especially a <a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/blob/master/wndw.md" target="_blank">MarkDown version of WNDW available</a> tracked with git and hosted on github for folks to <a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/fork" target="_blank">fork</a>, edit, and <a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/pulls" target="_blank">submit pull requests</a>. This is an opportunity to engage with the wider readership of WNDW in order to incorporate edits directly, which can filter up to formalized versions, as well as this web version.</p>
<h2>@TODO</h2>
<p>There&#39;s <a href="https://github.com/wrought/wireless-networking-in-the-developing-world/issues" target="_blank">a stack of issues on github</a> to handle all the opportunities and tasks associated with converting and sharing this document far and wide!</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wndw/" term="wndw"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/pandoc/" term="pandoc"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/conversion/" term="conversion"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/odt/" term="odt"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/html/" term="html"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/markdown/" term="markdown"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/mediawiki markup/" term="mediawiki markup"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wikisource/" term="wikisource"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wireless/" term="wireless"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/ict4d/" term="ict4d"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/mesh/" term="mesh"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/sudo mesh/" term="sudo mesh"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/peoplesopen.net/" term="peoplesopen.net"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes from Bay Area Drupal Camp (BADcamp)]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/notes-from-bay-area-drupal-camp-(badcamp)/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/notes-from-bay-area-drupal-camp-(badcamp)/</id>
    <published>2013-10-30T10:59:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T11:11:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Non-Profit Summit</h2>
<p>Came in late. Marsh Arts Center in Berkeley has terrible wifi service for an event where apparently some folks want to be connected to the internet.</p>
<h3>Tech Soup Global</h3>
<p>Caught the post-lunch keynote, 30 min talk. Pretty interesting hearing about the work of a progressive team inside of a large global non-profit. In sum, if you believe you can deliver, push ahead and build the world you want to work in, even if it rides against the stream.</p>
<p>Really interesting content, slides are perfect notes for this circumstance, will link here. </p>
<h3>CRM breakout</h3>
<p><em>Metaphor for CRM:</em> it is like writing an outline for a novel&mdash;enough detail, but not too much.</p>
<p>Recommend: build the tiniest possible thing and starting to use it and help it grow.</p>
<blockquote><p>The most important thing about planning a CRM project is being <em>un-sentimental</em> about the organizational needs. Do not elevate ‘wants’ to ‘needs’ while also not demoting ‘needs’ to ‘wants’.</p>
</blockquote>


<p>Listen for moments of surprise and encourage those. Identify warning signs early and catch them ASAP, early, without being paranoid. </p>
<p>Need to change from Technology Advocate to Subject-Matter Expert in your organization (recognize this).</p>
<p>Recognize that this stuff is only interesting to technologists / nerds, not to everyone!</p>
<p>!! Opportunity case: TI Alumni have this issue of older folks not needing some fancy things they see as young and unnecessary. On the other hand, they want to see what a new system will look like before pursuing it. Unofortunately, as the tech person has to say, if we could show you what it would look like&mdash;we would have built it already! SO, what is the use case?<br>!!! The user wants to build a <em>real</em> mock-up using an actual crm instance, <a href="http://wordpress.com/" target="_blank">wordpress.com</a>-style. This leaves the opportunity for running a simple, blog-style CRM, then upgrading for freemium features, and ultimately to move to independent instances, development contracts, etc.<br>!!! Need to investigate pantheon, aws, other drupal hosting (and cloud hosting) services to determine how to hack this with an MVP.</p>
<h4>What about modularity&mdash;why drupal at all?</h4>
<p>If you are using drupal as a brochureware, why would you bother integrating CRM? Probably you should not, unless you are doing <em>actual</em> interaction with your user, such as doing event registration, etc.</p>
<h4>Technologies</h4>
<ul>
<li>Springboard</li>
<li>Blackbaud? (Convio ancestor)</li>
<li>Salesforce (force.com)</li>
<li>Red Hen (built FDBD, for-drupal-by-drupalers, vs civicrm)</li>
<li>CiviCRM</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bay Area Video Coalition (BAVC)</h2>
<p>Jennifer Gilmen and Mark Hellar.</p>
<p>Community center in San Francisco. Support independent media, including a public access tv station&mdash;which motivated the move to drupal in the first place some years ago.</p>
<p>Center of Investigative Reporting \&amp; them are interested in measuring impact.</p>
<p>Part of documentary filmmaker coop called New Day Films, want to use drupal + salesforce, etc.</p>
<p>At the center of quite a number of different kinds of orgs. From cities to youth programs, independent producers, public meda, companies, etc.</p>
<p>Bid on SF public access TV station some years ago. AT\&amp;T rigged the laws to choke major city contracts for public access. Funding was going down to $170,000 / year, which is nothing! Not much to support all the good work they were doing there already.</p>
<p>Wanted to provide a lot of functionality for the public broadcast station, was possible due to work from the  Denver Open Media project. Needs more development!!! Contact them.</p>
<p>!! Side-note… It seems like the advantage of the html5 side of the web is that folks can access the full stack of the application and can therefore reproduce issues and do bug-fixing. However, when you have server-side software, there is a limitation to reproduce the same applications in order to actually work on them in the abstract. Some systems try to address this in some fashion that allow you to more closely reproduce the sites and applications <em>as they may exist in the wild</em> but usually it is a pain in the ass! E.g. django has fixtures, drupal has site archetypes (erg, what is the technical name for this?).<br>!!! So how to fix this? Unclear, is there a standard or simple way to make your site, private, safe, yet clonable?</p>
<p>Lots of discussion of webforms and integrating with salseforce using springboard. This is boring. Is this really the state of the art on the web for independent and public media coalitions? What is the next-generation of this type of work?</p>
<p>Honky-dory that program folks can interoperate with this system fairly elegantly&mdash;the state of the art is perhaps (not restricted but) shaped by the use of folks who are going to be implenenting programs and working on services provided by non-profits, etc.</p>
<ul>
<li>Perhaps it is /using/ data, visualizing it, and allowing <em>complex interaction</em>. <ul>
<li>What does “complex interaction” look like? <ul>
<li>doing lots of things with the data, storing states, allowing it to interoperate with other sources and services, being able to share and then build a review/comment layer on top of this.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>This is perhaps why I am very interested in using drupal as a back-end to some javascript engines like knockout.js.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>BAVC has a program for documentary filmmakers to publish and share content, which automatically gets archived in the internet archive&mdash;stored in “Community Media” archive.</p>
<p>Ideally, folks should be able to upload content to their local library, ship it to BAVC, publish to the website, and archive it with Internet Archive&mdash;<em>automagically</em>.</p>
<p>Created a website for city and county of San Francisco, <a href="http://goconnectsf.org/" target="_blank">GoConnectSF</a> with youth center digital filmmaking programs.</p>
<p>If you want to see code email markh@bavc.org, for programs, email jennifer@bavc.org.</p>
<h2>Drupal 8 Security</h2>
<p>Presentation formatted in Ubuntu font ;)</p>
<p>Drupal.org acts as a security gateway to drupal modules, but as modules move to github/etc, we&#39;ll see the security landscape.</p>
<p>Examples of systems having their repositories compromised in the last couple of years:</p>
<h3>Versioning</h3>
<ul>
<li>FreeBSD compromised with third-party packages in conversion between cvs to subversion.<ul>
<li>Took a while to find out what had been changed due to central cvs control mechanism</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Linux Kernel: This happened a few years ago to Linux as well<ul>
<li>Luckily, with git it was relatively easier to determine if something had been tampered with</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>API</h3>
<p>Drupal - Uses PHP, Procedural hook system &gt; modularity: PSR/Symfony (paradigm)</p>
<ul>
<li>Emphasis for Drupal is to put more emphasis on the Services module, need to keep eye on REST security moving forward.</li>
<li>Comparative examples outline differences</li>
</ul>
<h3>Django vs. Drupal</h3>
<p>“The fact that Django is so object-oriented inherently reduces th epotential for vulnerabilities (even by mistake) that are often seen in other procedural code because data will typically travel through a single common layer (or class) whereby data can be cleaned, security checks conducted, etc.”</p>
<p>Movement to Object Oriented model in Drupal 8, as part of a move to professionalize PHP.</p>
<p>Speaker: “Often compared to a field of Anarchy, where things act their own way.”</p>
<ul>
<li>php == “anarchy”</li>
</ul>
<p>Lookup: “PHP: The Right Way”, www.php-fig.org</p>
<p>Dries Buytaert article on PHP over Java for Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>More approachable for amateur programmers.</li>
<li>Also, audience of Drupal did not include conservative bodies like Governments<ul>
<li>However, since, these adopters have come.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Opportunity to standardize and professionalize the application, without becoming rigid.</li>
</ul>
<h3>API Security</h3>
<p>All have methods for filtering dangerous content.</p>
<ul>
<li>Drupal<ul>
<li>Filters on output rather than input! Same as WordPress, unlike others</li>
<li>Input filters (t(), check_plain, filter_xss, db_query); entities; form tokens; autho cookies; password hashing &amp; salting (SHA512), Twig</li>
<li>Twig is a new Drupal 8 templating framework&mdash;a dangerous attack vector.<ul>
<li>US Government found that majority of security vulnerabilities live in templates!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Some good database abstraction which sort of serves as an ORM.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>WordPress<ul>
<li>Filters (wp_filter_kses(), $wpdb)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Security Management</h3>
<p>Drupal has the most active security infrastructure, especially comparative to WordPress.</p>
<ul>
<li>Security Team exists to:<ul>
<li>Resolve issues</li>
<li>Assist module maintainers</li>
<li>Documentation</li>
<li>Responsible disclosure</li>
<li>Secure coding guide</li>
<li>Provide full project review for drupal.org modules. (this security vector).<ul>
<li>Seems like it&#39;s possible to resolve this “github” issue by piping endpoints.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>WordPress<ul>
<li>Does have a security team, but they take a background role</li>
<li>Many folks seeking to do security for work</li>
<li>Don&#39;t set up monitoring, but they stop the hackers pre-emptively.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>!Idea: Java vs. PHP: Security Implications of Language Choice for Web Applications - James Walden (Northern Kentucky University). </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://freshmeat.net" target="_blank">freshmeat.net</a></li>
</ul>
<p>A lot of focus over the years on WordPress plugins</p>
<ul>
<li>20% of top plugins, including majority of ecommerce plugins had serious vulnerabilities<ul>
<li>Researchers found that open source community did not take responsibility for security of community developments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Community Comparison</h3>
<p>Essentially, there are trade-offs between platforms from a security perspective, e.g. “ease of use” versus centralized management.</p>
<h3>Security Issue: Drupal Core</h3>
<p>Some Recent Vulnerabilities</p>
<p>Drupal:</p>
<ul>
<li>Image module<ul>
<li>Not checking whether a valid token was used to create an image derivative (could create on the fly, execute a DoS attack)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Context module<ul>
<li>Not a sufficient check whether you had access&mdash;could gain access.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>WordPress</p>
<ul>
<li>eCommerce plugin<ul>
<li>Many issues with XSS</li>
<li>insufficient level of content filtering with wp_kses_post()</li>
<li>In another point, had not checked for proper permissions to allow only ordering of published items.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Compliance</h3>
<p>FISMA, standards for government bodies</p>
<p>PCI, credit card standards</p>
<p>Lots of toggles to form compliance:</p>
<h3>Roles &amp; Permissions</h3>
<p>Drupal:</p>
<ul>
<li>Very granular, but very complex that can generate vulnerabilities</li>
<li>However, this is possible to manage better with OA and WorkBench modules.</li>
</ul>
<p>WordPress has more separation of administrative layer.</p>
<h3>Federated Identity &amp; Multi-Factor Authentication</h3>
<p>Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>OpenID, OAuth, LDAP, Google Authenticator, TFA/SmS, YubiKey, Duo, wikid, SAML: NIH Login, CAS,: OMB MAX, PIV</li>
<li>Features expanding for authentication</li>
<li>SAML and CAS are secure authentication protocols for many government agencies.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Vulnerability Assessment</h3>
<p>Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>security review, coder/secure code review, dpscan, security scanner</li>
</ul>
<h3>Hardening</h3>
<p>Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>Hardened Drupal, Guardr, Paranoia<ul>
<li>Guardr install profile activiates many helpful</li>
<li>Acquia maintains a great overview of security modules with Drupal Scout</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>WordPress</p>
<ul>
<li>Integrated security plugins (Better WPSecurity, BulletProof Security), Secure WordPress.A</li>
</ul>
<h3>Continuous Monitoring</h3>
<ul>
<li>By default, you often get a wealth of data which is difficult to filter</li>
<li>Collecting lots of data, but watching the important stuff allows capability of reducing threats and addressing attacks.<br>w </li>
<li>A lot of security modules are at a nascent stage.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Hosting Platforms and Environment</h3>
<p>Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>LAMP: Apache/Nginx/IIs, Mysql/Maria/PostgreSQL/MSSQL/Oracle, PHP 5.3</li>
<li>Follow fork to MariaDB<ul>
<li>Oracle was becoming less transparent in terms of security</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Drupal.org Security Incident</h3>
<ul>
<li>Breach of drupal.org, compromised</li>
<li>Had to reset passwords</li>
<li>Third-party software breached: undisclosed</li>
<li>With drupal, you never walk alone.<ul>
<li>Depending on Apache, Cash, Chef, Solar, Maria, Linux, etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Security Ninja</h3>
<ul>
<li>Only possibly by effectively understanding the other components to become a <em>Security Rockstar</em>!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Why users are irrational and what we can do about it</h2>
<h3>Heuristics</h3>
<p>&quot;Ferrari drivers are erratic, look out!&quot;</p>
<p>Help us make decisions really quickly — “rules of thumb” </p>
<h3>Cognitive Biases</h3>
<p>When we have a heuristic that is in some fashion illogical or erroneous</p>
<h4>Example</h4>
<p>Different ways of displaying the expanded form of 9! yields different incorrect results</p>
<ul>
<li>Starting with 1 gives ~500</li>
<li>Starting with 9 gives ~4200</li>
<li>Total is ~ 36,000?</li>
</ul>
<p>Humans have a bias toward initial data for instance.</p>
<h4>Inspirational White Dudes</h4>
<ul>
<li>Khaneman</li>
<li>Tversky</li>
<li>Thaler</li>
<li>Slovic</li>
<li>Arielly<ul>
<li>More down-to-earth, also good TED talks on irrationality</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Do we trust these folks? They are pioneers in psychology, which is convenient since there are supposedly controlled empirical experiments</p>
<ul>
<li>Pioneers of usability research /before/ it existed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Many Biases</p>
<h4>Common Types</h4>
<ul>
<li>Confirmation bias<ul>
<li>Will gravitate to data that confirms existing beliefs</li>
<li>Ex: searching for “the right solution” online can simply yield the same /incorrect/ solution<ul>
<li>Designers also say, 51% are better (but is there really significance?) often in usability testing</li>
<li>Careful of body language to encourage confirmation (leaning in with a tester)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Approaches<ul>
<li>Provide answers, not raw data; provide anecdotes, not statistics; observe users not metrics</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Congruence bias<ul>
<li>People rely on direct hypothesis testing rather than indirect testing.</li>
<li>Drupal is a perfect example of this bias. There are many ways to do things, surprising sometimes.</li>
<li>Surveyed all the customers, so therefore this is what we should do (but what about the other users?)</li>
<li>Designers don&#39;t look outside of the sphere of work (pick between 3 options—but what about outside the scope?)</li>
<li>Approaches<ul>
<li>Keep eyes out for strange pathways, unnecessary solutions</li>
<li>Encourage stakeholders to broaden the base, compare against competitors and similar products, look cross-industry</li>
<li>Designers should test against competition, not within merely available options</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Curse of Knowledge<ul>
<li>!RAMPANT in the Drupal community</li>
<li>Assume huge amounts of knowledge for the users for language and nomenclature<ul>
<li>Not everyone knows what a <em>node</em> is!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Assumption that search box is always in upper right corner</li>
<li>Language like “boolean, float, integer” for fields UI&mdash;really inaccessible vocabulary</li>
<li>Designers may adopt “new icons” or new images, but is it necessarily understandable to your user?<ul>
<li>Be careful venturing out into new territory, at least use some other affordance to encourage users to break pattern</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Approaches<ul>
<li>Users should use ubiquitous patterns wherever possible</li>
<li>Use video to capture contextual inquiry to put usage in perspective</li>
<li>Test patterns you already consider “established”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Illusion of Correlation<ul>
<li>Misinterpreting coincidental events for causal relationships.</li>
<li>Users explain that one action necessarily generates another response, but may not be the case.</li>
<li>Seeing sales or traffic go down after launch of new site&mdash;maybe there are other factors</li>
<li>Changing the design and finding that it tests more poorly.</li>
<li>Approaches<ul>
<li>Ensure feedback is limited to the user&#39;s task to allow them to construct causal relations where appropriate, and not the opposite</li>
<li>Focus the question. Sales went down, but what else happened, what was going on?</li>
<li>Designers should limit the variables to ensure less convolution.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Loss Aversion<ul>
<li>Folks strongly prefer avoiding losses over acquiring gains</li>
<li>Another, sub-bias is: memory of pleasant events fades quickly, versus unpleasant fading slowly.</li>
<li>Users may feel connected to things they have made, don&#39;t want to lose them</li>
<li>Stakeholders don‘t want to feel like they’ve wasted investment by throwing code away.<ul>
<li>aka “Sunk Cost Fallacy” - spent all this time working on it, so the newness “loses” all that previous investment.</li>
<li>The issue with this is not asessing the development in the context of time, that overall there are opportunities to build new things that will take less times.</li>
<li>!&quot;Your only have the future, the past doesn&#39;t exist!&quot;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Designers get stuck to carefully-crafted elements (e.g. skeumorphic button) that add unnecessary dependency<ul>
<li>Emotional attachment, rather than ephemeral things</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Approaches<ul>
<li>Can use loss aversion in ethical and transparent ways to drive stickiness</li>
<li>Encourage stakeholders to assess future costs, rather than only past cost</li>
<li>Designers need a Zen approach to have emotional detachment&mdash;move on, create something new.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Cognitive_Biases" target="_blank">List of Cognitive Biases</a><ul>
<li>Many more!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>!Anchors can encourage the user to make a choice that seems reasonable in context, rather than actual cost and value (e.g. three options, middle highlighted). </p>
<h4>Ethical Considerations</h4>
<ul>
<li>may not be illegal or necessarily wrong, but it could be unethical.</li>
<li>Check out the [](Dark Patterns Library):<ul>
<li>Already opted-in to receiving spam emails after signing up for something.</li>
<li>This has been used for good&mdash;organ donors in Europe, opt-out system.</li>
<li>Way more organs available in Europe</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>! Metric: Consider whether your use of biases, patterns, etc in a way that is aligned with the needs of your user.</p>
<h3>Design Patterns</h3>
<p>Acquia is assembling a design patterns document. One of them:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#39;m worthy of your trust<ul>
<li>I say what I mean and I do what I say. It&#39;s not in my nature to trick, conceal, handwave, or manipulate. My success is directly aligned with yours and your good opinion is invaluable</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Questions</h3>
<p>Sunk-Cost Fallacy Strategies</p>
<ul>
<li>Do an actual calculation of support cost</li>
<li>However, another cognitive bias to frustrate this<ul>
<li>Folks have a tendency to value near-term costs over long-term costs. </li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Data Management Applications with Drupal as your Framework</h2>
<p>!Tripal - Genomics in Drupal</p>
<ul>
<li>Generic Model Organism Database - DB schema</li>
</ul>
<p>Kept building data apps, so eventually decided to make it more modular, reusable.</p>
<p>Saw drupal, has nice features:</p>
<ul>
<li>User, roles, auth</li>
<li>Forms, data handling, etc</li>
</ul>
<h3>Data development</h3>
<p>Chose to write data application without CCK, so this is all in code.</p>
<ul>
<li>Existing built-in schema update and <code>drush make</code></li>
<li>Data source/uplink:<ul>
<li>Links to outside data sources with financial info and academic data</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Upload/import w/ cron and batch</li>
<li>Create read-only data mirrors</li>
</ul>
<p>Chose drupal to make highly modular design</p>
<p>Use case requires granular access control for each module</p>
<p>Can have as many or few roles as you need, granular permissions</p>
<p>In terms of content access, can use built-in realms and grants</p>
<p>Uses Content and Forms features to develop platform</p>
<p>Advantage of Drupal is “aspect-oriented” paradigm rather than MVC</p>
<ul>
<li>Flexibility is integral, things change on a regular term</li>
<li>The module handles everything concerning the particular aspect<ul>
<li>The alumni module handles the fields, the submission, form handling, etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Usage of hooks (actions) as callbacks through the standard process</li>
</ul>
<h2>Demo Framework</h2>
<p>Keeping it simple, this is fairly simple (though lengthy) install:</p>
<p><a href="https://drupal.org/project/df" target="_blank">Demo Framework</a></p>
<p>This is a way to showcase a site to potential customers quickly, not just describe drupal features.</p>
<p>Acquia is behind it, but committed to community involvement and open source—it already is open source.</p>
<p>To work with a client, ended up developing a new use case for a proper, thinner framework based on DF for sites:</p>
<p><a href="https://drupal.org/project/lightning" target="_blank">Lightning</a></p>
<p>!Basically, as far as I can tell, this project is a low-level closely drupal-integrated solution for making a data application</p>
<h2>Project Prophylaxis</h2>
<p>A <em>prophylactic</em> is a mechanism to prevent the transmission of disease.</p>
<p><em>Practicing Project Prophylaxis</em> is the practice of using legally protectie measures when working with clients by contract.</p>
<h3>Exposed</h3>
<p>You can feel exposed as a developer, designer, engineer, or even member of a new business.</p>
<p>Crowd is mostly shop owners / directors. A few contractors. One “other”.</p>
<h3>Client Relationship</h3>
<p>Consider the relationship through the entire lifecycle of the process.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Choose clients wisely</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Know your skills / comfort zone</li>
<li>Align personalities / mission</li>
<li>Understand what success looks like<br>** Have metrics for success?</li>
</ul>
<p>Often, go through discovery phase, work on spec (for pay), allow room for alternative vendors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Interestingly, this is never the case.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you‘re crafting a contract, you’ll be agreeing to deliverables. Discovery phase gives a chance to get a feel for client and scope.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All those present are agile, so this is a consistent process</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Q:</strong> How detailed is that spec?</p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> Depends. Outline as:</p>
<ul>
<li>UX Artefacts</li>
<li>WireFrames</li>
<li>Assets</li>
<li>Tech Strategy</li>
<li>Information / content</li>
</ul>
<p>Use a boiler plate contract that effectively agrees that the client will pay. The deliverables are specified out in particular. Some use a time &amp; materials contract—hourly work, in good faith in estimates, but the client can derail at any time with crazy requests. If you&#39;re not really strict about that you can run through their budget with half a project. This is important for your record. You may be legally protected, but you have a business obligation to right somehow.</p>
<p>The message here:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>There&#39;s a lot of gray area</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Every client is different, need to foster the relationship while also using the same protections across.</p>
<h3>Negotiation and contracts</h3>
<p>Scopes of Work can be 20 pages long! These aren‘t necessary, detestable. As long as you have an understanding going forward, not everything has to be in the Scope of Work, you’ll have good legal protection.</p>
<p>A good lawyer is going to write a boilerplate contract in your best favor. When you go in to signing someone else&#39;s contract, be aware that they want to have an edge, have terms that are in their favor.</p>
<ul>
<li>Negotiation tips:<ul>
<li>Confidence<ul>
<li>Most clients feel like they&#39;re being wrong or mean, have to be comfortable being matter-of-fact. Ask for stuff, and say “No”.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Strawmen<ul>
<li>Talk to someone else to get feedback in the middle of a negotiation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Advocates<ul>
<li>Most important factor&mdash;need to connect with your advocate to make it through e.g. “procurement”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Battle of the Forms:<ul>
<li>Proposals, SOWs, MSAs, POs, yadda yadda…</li>
<li>Be careful because MSA language may supercede SOW terms about when/how to get paid.</li>
<li>Do search for “indemn” strike out indemnification against you.</li>
<li>Also warranties and representations</li>
<li>Don&#39;t assign rights of your toolkit to the client! (Careful of the “open source” clauses)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Contract Basics<ul>
<li>Money (Approvals and satisfaction), liability (reps/warranties and indemnity), and Rights (don&#39;t “assign” your toolkit</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Money<ul>
<li>“Posession is 9/10ths of th elaw.”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Majority of Gabe&#39;s clients are using fixed-pay. Number one concern is scope creep versus milestone and deliverable. Some of his biggest clients use fairly generic language.</p>
<p>Be careful of acceptance statements and satisfaction language.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Full discretion” besides “reasonable discretion”?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Difference between a SOW and Terms&mdash;the simplicity of individual words like “sole”</p>
<h3>Getting it Done</h3>
<ul>
<li>Discover and set expectations: communication, risks, requirements</li>
<li>Meet expectations: Build it well, product reviews</li>
<li>Manage expectations: status, scope control</li>
<li>Invoice early and often</li>
<li>Be consistent, proactive, and reinforce value</li>
<li>Write it down.</li>
</ul>
<p>Metaphor: the same way you pay attention to your servers you should pay attention to your contracts&mdash;you can get hacked.</p>
<p>Agreeing to it in writing&mdash;<em>you&#39;ve got a contract!</em></p>
<p>!Arbitration can be <em>gamed</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Example: one of Gabe&#39;s clients had a client that extended the cost quite a bit, making it expensive.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>BIG LEVER:</strong> Put an attorney&#39;s fees clause in the contract, so you can argue for $30k-$40k contracts.</p>
<h3>Clients Gone Wild</h3>
<ul>
<li>Challenge: protecting clients from themselves—stakes are high!</li>
<li>Contracts in Agile work, when to use change order? SOW?</li>
<li>Manage expectations while protecting yourself in T&amp;M: keep focused on MVP and remember your backlog<ul>
<li>Can use the backlog as a good metaphor and communications tool with clients. Use this feedback speedily!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Stay strong</li>
<li>Non-payments, silent treatment, rude behavior</li>
</ul>
<h3>Firing Clients</h3>
<p>Trying to be <strong>partners</strong> with all of your clients, on the <em>survivor island</em>.</p>
<p>When there is <strong>animosity</strong> get away as fast as you can.</p>
<p>!Know what <strong>indemnity</strong> means! Pay your lawyer some money now to save you tons later!</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>Choose your clients with discretion</li>
<li>Always wear a contract</li>
<li>Make sure it fits</li>
<li>Foster the relationship</li>
<li>Be the stable one</li>
<li>Communicate</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have to… <strong><em>Walk Away</em></strong></p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/BADcamp/" term="BADcamp"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/drupal/" term="drupal"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/cms/" term="cms"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/php/" term="php"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/software/" term="software"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/unconference/" term="unconference"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/open source/" term="open source"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/community/" term="community"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/share/" term="share"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/talks/" term="talks"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/a-new-blog/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/a-new-blog/</id>
    <published>2013-10-30T01:06:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T01:18:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Launching a new blog. This site is static HTML generated by Hexo, a nodejs application. I write the content in markdown first, which compiles to HTML.</p>
<h2>What now?</h2>
<p>Unclear.</p>
<p>I&#39;d like to take notes and share them very simply.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/weblog/" term="weblog"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/plumbing/" term="plumbing"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hexo/" term="hexo"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/nodejs/" term="nodejs"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/markdown/" term="markdown"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Social Movement Manifesto]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/an-open-social-movement-manifesto.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/an-open-social-movement-manifesto.html/</id>
    <published>2013-07-09T19:32:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:52:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have found theories for social movements, especially civil rights, anti-war, and even protest generally, to be wholly insufficient to capture substantial aspects of our current struggle for openness.</p>
<p>Openness is not merely some product of technology, nor is it some new technology itself. Openness affords public good akin to notions of democracy. Both constitute negotiations of appropriate action, and fairness. We have seen various communities organize in support of openness, and it is about time we leverage this network structure&mdash;in fact there is no such luxury to wait:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Exponential Growth</strong> - The struggle for openness is directly in opposition to the desires of many incumbent institutions and firms, especially those who benefit through money and power/control. There is no time to grow linearly, even by a factor greater than one. For every interval, we need to grow at a greater rate than the previous interval. Next year, we cannot merely double, but rather, we must outpace ourselves from the previous year and prepare to grow even faster the next. This implies:<ul>
<li>Time is completely of the essence and we should be wary of delay and derailment strategies that wear us down.</li>
<li>We must be extremely clever and use all available tools to bend any of our linear growth into exponential ones such as via media that afford ease of coordination, automation and amplification, as well as both traditional and experimental funding mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Diversity of Tactics</strong> - If the first principle can be illustrated by a steep, exponential curve, then this second can be thought of through the <em>long tail</em>, the log, or exponential inverse. If we consolidate efforts and rally behind unified fronts, we can produce great results, akin to the beginning “head” component of a log distribution. However, there is substantial value in niche approaches and opportunities, the many small areas where openness can be adopted, often in unique or atypical ways. The sum of the long tail very well may be equivalent in size to the head of the curve.<ul>
<li>Consolidation can be advantageous, but exclusively it is antithetical to openness itself. It cannot be the only option.</li>
<li>Perhaps even greater than doubling impact, a diversity of tactics supports positive feedback, a range of ideas and materials that can be fed into other open initiatives in fashions we cannot predict.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Peer-to-Peer Structure</strong> - Of the many lessons learned from legacy institutions that employ closed and proprietary systems, among them is that concentration of power breeds unfairness and injustice. This lesson must be intuited for openness to succeed. Not only the concession, but the active pursuit of peer-oriented models is the only viable alternative to trading one set of regimes for another, or merely squishing regimes into a slightly smaller, but still dominant position.<ul>
<li>Thus we must address hierarchy at every level and work toward deconstructing it, even if it will take time.</li>
<li>We must also commit to resolving conflicts and disputes swiftly through solidarity since divided we currently are conquered.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Some examples:</p>
<ol>
<li><em><a href="http://kopimism.org/" target="_blank">Open Access Manifesto</a></em> - Simply put, Aaron was right. This is a moral issue. We have an imperative to reject the rules, and abide by them, however we see fit, in the aim to set information free.</li>
<li><em>Public Policy</em> - It is not the sole struggle of the Openness movement to see results from the political process. All movements for social change today must confront the deep and crippling corruption of the democratic process and state accountability in a global context. We must pursue this avenue, it is not fruitless, but we also cannot lose sight of the need for our movement to operate at every level.</li>
<li><em>Infrastructure</em> - Every bit counts. When we have the opportunity, or the privilege, we must invest in building lasting, or temporary, infrastructure to support openness. This means: open a hackerspace, donate to good causes, find ways to hack livelihood for yourselves and others to do things in the open, engage in public discourse, engage in politics at the local level up, make art and express yourself creatively in ways that promote openness, buy land, buy businesses, buy banks&mdash;<em>set it all free!</em></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/openness/" term="openness"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/social movements/" term="social movements"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/civil rights/" term="civil rights"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/anti-war/" term="anti-war"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/protest/" term="protest"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/exponential growth/" term="exponential growth"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/diversity of tactics/" term="diversity of tactics"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/long tail/" term="long tail"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/head/" term="head"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/tail/" term="tail"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/peer-to-peer/" term="peer-to-peer"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/p2p/" term="p2p"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hack the planet/" term="hack the planet"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[London, Cambridge, Oxford]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/london-cambridge-oxford.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/london-cambridge-oxford.html/</id>
    <published>2013-07-09T12:27:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is true much of the journey requires travel, logistics, negotiation of new landscapes, but the wandering can feel quite good. I flew in to South London at Gatwick, made the mistake of traveling farthest from my destination, so I took a long train through london, then a connection to King‘s Cross station to Cambridge. A friend set me up for the night at his new flat, and in the morning I walked just a few blocks to the Cambridge PLOS office. It wasn’t long in the UK until I began to take issue with the absurdity of placeness here. Every tiny street has its own name, and every little building. Often place names differ completely from address, and often addresses become complex since streets need not follow conventions like odds on one side, evens on the other. And good luck finding a street sign to know where you are. It is a comical, ironical place, but I do appreciate that for the most part, places are built to human dimensions, and confusion, more than anything, stems from history, the beaten path as it were. </p>
<p>In cambridge I met some of the members of Makespace, a new hackerspace with great institutional support and a fantastic location provided through a relationship with King&#39;s College. In just a few months, the members built up quite a bit of infrastructure, providing a full toolshop including laser cutters (one in service, the other large but out of commission at the moment), 3D printer, and a store room full of all the necessary nicnacs. A clever little move was to use clear bins for member ephemera on a member shelf in the hallway—keeping things quite orderly, but transparent to get a clue onthe types of materials other members are tinkering with at the moment. The general governance of the group is odd—there are three founders who act as directors and make the necessary decisions for the space, including allocation of funds. There is some layer of trust in which members, especially those who had been around for some time, were relied upon more heavily to work things out and improve the functioning of the space. There are general discussions on the email list, and general meetings, to work out different points of view, etc. There are more than a handful systems in place to manage the space, including a sort of “training the trainer” approach that requires a designated party to train you on using specific equipment before you can take it on yourself. This is for safety, and for the preservation of the equipment. </p>
<p>I had two particularly fruitfull exchanges with folks at Makespace. First, I was barely able to make it in, save posting on a meetup event that happened to be advertised for the night I was in town. The space is not open to the public generally, only for events and member-sponsored guests. this was taken to the extreme since leaving the space required a key, or breaking the glass on an emergency exit button. When my original tour guide and host had to leave, I asked to stick around to coordinate with my local friend to crash that night, and had to be “transferred” to another member to stick around. Lucky enough, they were both very welcoming, so it wasn‘t too much trouble. On the other hand, this is yet another case I’ve found of serving member needs with little infrastructure to support public access.</p>
<p>Second, I spoke with Rachel Raynes, artist in residence with the Raspberry Pi Foundation. She makes cool exploratory things with raspi&#39;s and represents their creative side at various events and conferences, etc. She was very supportive of a bay area <a href="http://ba.chgrp.org/#outsiders" target="_blank">hacker-in-residence</a> idea, we agreed similar such opportunities are absolutely necessary both on the side of creative projects and on the side of funding out-of-the-box thinkers. Through our discussion I also got to hear of an on-going thread at makespace about how to provide access and membership. On the one hand, some contend the institutional model of garnering donations from organizations. On the other hand is the accrual of income from membership dues. the discussion on hand at the moment concerns rates, and level of access, depending on the ability to pay the membership fee. For instance, there seems to be sympathy for financial hardship, but on the other, not necessarily the same perspective for students or folks who would claim they are unable to contribute as much, generally. It is a <a href="http://hackerspaces.org/wiki/Design_Patterns" target="_blank">hacker pattern</a> to offer a full and “starving hacker” rate. Of course, patterns are not rules at all, and our different approaches to this problem fit different contexts and help inform our overall strategies. Our diversity is not only a boon, but integral.</p>
<p>Our approach at sudo room is to both provide public access as an organizational goal, and to allow for sliding-scale contributions (or hopefully non-monetary using a fair system). This addresses two complexities:</p>
<ol>
<li>How do we approach access to resources for communities that do not have or choose to exercise the privilege to enter such spaces, especially those who would very much benefit from the community and the infrastructure itself?</li>
<li>How do we make governance of the organization democratic, in a sense that all folks who use the space can have a serious voice in its functioning?</li>
</ol>
<p>I think our solution is incomplete, but am very proud of the attempted approach. It is now our responsibility to improve it and accomplish the sort of diversity of perspective, and stakholdership, that we know is necessary and fruitful overall.</p>
<p>When I made it to London, I eventually wound up at the London Hackspace, a hackerspace in Hackney. I was surprised the pun was not pervasive, but pleased enough with various other puns in the space ;). </p>
<p>First of all, this is their new location as of some time this year (I believe the spring?), and it is HUGE. If there is anyone in the UK area looking to hold some hacker event, I say lobby the London Hackspace. The entrance is in the back through a large parking lot (confusing since the whole front of the building is on Hackney street). The ground floor has a quiet room, an electronics work bench, a lounge, a recording studio, a restroom with shower, a classroom, and general hacking space. Downstairs has the biohacking space (a closet, much bigger than the former storage closet they used before—people can actually sit or stand at benches here), a woodshop, a metal shop, shelves of various materials, an open workshop area, a bicycle repair stand, and boxes of various things still unpacked from the move. </p>
<p>Chatting with a few members, I came to understand the basic governance and the history of the space. They were in a much more cramped location before, and all were glad to have moved to this new location in the same general area. Things are doocratic, encouraging folks to work stuff out on their own, and to organize together to get things they want and see things change as needed. There is a board of elected folks, with a pattern to change 3 members every year, totalling 9, and cycling at a rate of 3 years—though there is no hard and fast rule not to be re-elected for many terms anyway. This group makes financial decisions, signs necessary contracts, and resolves disputes. When they had more money in the small space, they would allocate funds to tools and projects, but now they are strapped with rent for their grand space and encourage members to find interest amongst some others, and pool some money together to buy whatever it is they need. Often things are donated, or found cheaply, so this is not too bad. </p>
<p>Over the weekend in London, I went to two hackathons, especially to meet up with <a href="http://twitter.com/evo_mri" target="_blank">Daniel Mietchen</a> to collaborate on extending a Commons media importer to upload <a href="http://github.com/wrought/open-access-media-importer" target="_blank">Open Access videos to Youtube</a>. We got a lot of work in, and started a few other good threads, but the project is not yet finished ;). The first event was <a href="http://hack4ac.com/" target="_blank">#hack4ac</a>, where participants tried to demonstrate the power and utility of the <a href="http://creativecommons.org" target="_blank">CC-BY license</a>. The next was a medical-themed event put on by BMJ at the Hub Westminster. I was very pleased with the venue, and am considering using it in the future for other events. The projects were very excellent at both events, my personal favorite the <a href="http://twitter.com/oa_button" target="_blank">OA Button</a>.</p>
<p>Before leaving, I dipped my toe in Oxford, dropping in on some Digital Humanities workshops. It was intresting to see various perspectives on digital culture and opportunities from this group. One attendee quite eloquently shared, “The only future for humanities is digital.” There is no alternative, there are many questions and much uncertainty, but the future for the humanities will not remain in analog formats. I also got a chance to talk to a PhD student who researches “Questionnaires,” surprisingly old documents, especially used by enlightenment philosophers and public intellectuals to find out about things beyond their knowledge, such as life in the “New World.” It was a rather perplexing exchange. This researcher found a series of unpublished questionnaires. There is such a great opportunity for her to reach out and find swaths of similar documents, and connect to peer researchers. However, the fixation of mining out this academic gold of unpublished source work outweighs the opportunity to collaborate in the open. This is the precise challenge of humanities work. How does one overcome incentives as strong as career fodder? Ultimately, I left my suggestion on the table&mdash;publish the original scans, and the first transcriptions on a Github repository, seek out other researchers, contributors, transcribers, and source documents, then add them to the collection. This would be a fantstic exampe of networked research, publishable in its own right IMHO. This seems unlikely to happen now, oh well.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/uk/" term="uk"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/makespace/" term="makespace"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/london hackspace/" term="london hackspace"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/buses/" term="buses"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/transport/" term="transport"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trains/" term="trains"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/getting lost/" term="getting lost"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/friends/" term="friends"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/pubs/" term="pubs"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/beverages/" term="beverages"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/berlin.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/berlin.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-27T08:44:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T08:40:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My time in Berlin was studded with generous hospitality, coupled by sufficient aimless wandering. It was just enough time to poke my head about and really get a feel for the city. I was lucky when I arrived it was cloudy, then rainy, and kept on that pattern for most of my days there. The final few days were sun-filled and glorious. If there were better weather I would have seriously believed I could move right in. Even the summer cold was enough to remind me, I am a spoiled desert creature of California. That being said, I can still imagine spending time there… just not forever, or maybe just not the winter.</p>
<p>Berlin is a locus for the surrounding European area, and Germany itself, not to mention a harbor for various migrants and ex-pats. Some years and mini-generations of migration and gentrification have welcomed, shunned, embraced, discarded, and churned the city through. It is such a large city that development is plentiful, but does leave many buildings untouched, quite a bit of existing infrastructure is just fine as is. That was the remarkable side for me, while not an extraordinarily tall city with sky-scrapers, there are very large swaths with 4-5 story buildings, built close together. This affords space for various uses, from housing to business, squats to co-working, markets to hackerspaces. The narrative today is represented best through the squats of yore, like Tacheles, now closed by building owners staking claim across the city to fuel business districts, housing enclaves, gentrifiers, and the many people generally coming through the city. The culture of these spaces, the mentality in various modes of collectivity, individuality and creativity remain. </p>
<p>The other theme of Berlin that cannot be over-stated is division, and return. Separation exists presently, and historically, at every layer of local life, as well as for the passing visitor like myself or any other tourist. It is a cycle of unification, (re-)purposing, and (re-)establishing divisions. The wall is demarkated, referenced, and displayed in various locations, in a sort of shattered array of a time still in living memory. Portions of the city were vacant, or used one way before, and for something else now. Old is re-used in new fashion, to benefit and detriment. </p>
<p>But enough of my urbanist suggestions. </p>
<p>Many thanks to the friends and hosts who showed me about. C-base is a space ship entrance, or a 90s scifi soundstage, or a seasoned, smoky, hacker center of international recognition and deep local value. I was lucky enough to get a tour downstairs, with a dose of lore, including that my hand-scan identified me as an alien entrant, while my crew member escorted me past various control panels in the dimly lit and hazy basement. On our way to dig out an esoteric french research book in which both c-base and sudo room are examined, we walked in to an on-going interview with the local public radio. Without skipping a beat, my host picked up a conversation in an adjacent room and swiftly ran through the boilerplate questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What&#39;s a hacker?</li>
<li>What&#39;s a hackerspace?</li>
<li>What do you do here?</li>
</ul>
<p>Flawless responses, a small move for public understanding.</p>
<p>If you are in Berlin, go to C-base, drink a mate soda, and hack the planet. Seriously. The crew-members-only basement is especially decked out—and if you can find a guide to give you a tour, it would be well worth it. The energy and thought put in over time is endearing. On the other hand, there are defiant elements that make things difficult for the space to be inclusive, despite its growth in membership and importance in global hacker and hackerspace communities. The budget is centralized, and decisions are made in a large group meeting, projects approved, and funds provided. The space is fairly do-ocratic, but there are some present functions that try on the membership. For instance, maintaining the space for public use and supporting events can wear on time and patience of members. Secondly, some take issue with pervasive cigarette smoke, necessitating a smoke-free space, AFRA. I did not get a chance to visit AFRA, but I will have to on my next return. They are fairly new and I hope they grow!</p>
<p>On the other hand, I did have a chance to stop by CCC Berlin. I found making contact with hackerspace folks in Berlin—and there are many, plus many in-between spaces—was a bit difficult. Folks generally treated spaces as clubs, where exclusivity is not just a default but sort of important. Folks were not unfriendly, it is simply that general access is not a priority, and a bit of skepticism is held. Attending events or getting in contact with individual members to show you around is a good way to get in and talk to folks. C-base is very accessible, but other than that, these spaces serve a narrow function of serving their members more than other things. </p>
<p>I had a chance to visit Potsdam, the decadant imperial city of various historical empires of the region, including San Soucci, a castle/mansion of sorts. The city was a good glimpse of the active construction and visions of the exotic and of concentrated state power. It was worth to witness such a thing, as modern (and American) imperialism is mainly dislocated, obscured, and now passive/pervasive.</p>
<p>Near the end of my stay, I attended an unanticipated event at C-base with talks from: <a href="http://vimeo.com/69582065" target="_blank">Andreas Lehner</a> of <a href="http://ccc.de/" target="_blank">CCC</a>, <a href="http://vimeo.com/69580427" target="_blank">Moritz Bratl</a> of <a href="https://www.torservers.net/" target="_blank">torservers.net</a> a non-profit that supports participation in the Tor project, and by activist <a href="http://vimeo.com/69570248" target="_blank">Jacob Applebaum</a>. I recommend watching it. The stand-out thread was the illegal PRISM program, the extent of US abuse of power including through surveillance, and asylum for Edward Snowden. You will be&mdash;should&mdash;be shocked and activated. In sum, there is more we can do to support projects like <a href="http://torproject.org/" target="_blank">Tor</a>, and protecting or saving time for people who need it most. If you are interested in teaching journalists and lawyers how to send encrypted messages, <a href="http://twitter.com/wrought" target="_blank">let me know</a>.</p>
<p>Finally, if you go to Berlin, I recommend getting around on bicycle. The public transport is very good, but moving via bicycle is a special pleasure by itself.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/berlin/" term="berlin"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/c-base/" term="c-base"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/ccc/" term="ccc"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/ccc berlin/" term="ccc berlin"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/rain/" term="rain"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/sun/" term="sun"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/walls/" term="walls"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/subways/" term="subways"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/communism/" term="communism"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/capitalism/" term="capitalism"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/socialism/" term="socialism"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/post-conference.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/post-conference.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-23T05:58:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The train is nearly silent. There is a faint whistle, but quieter even than a rachetless-casette bike-ride through sparsely populated hills. I am on my way to Lausanne from Geneva, North of the lake. Tomorrow I will catch a bus to Berlin, which I now regret&mdash;who knows if I will get to sleep on the overnight ride, ha! Hopefully it will be worth the $70 savings? Heh, only one way to see.</p>
<h2>Hack the Planet</h2>
<p>I plan to visit <a href="http://fixme.ch/" target="_blank">fixme</a>, a hackerspace in Lausanne. While in Geneva, I had the privilege to enter Post Tenebras Lab (Latin for “after darkness” lab&mdash;a riff off a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post_tenebras_lux" target="_blank">common motto</a> in Geneva) along with fellow Wikimedian/Wikipedian conference attendees Daniel Mietchen, Lane Rasberry, and Andrea Zanni. We had a tour of the infrastructure so far, an in-space-cooked dinner supplied by PTL / coordinated by Andrea, plenty of rousing conversation, and general interest in further collaborations with <a href="http://ba.chgrp.org/" target="_blank">BACH</a> and <a href="http://sudoroom.org/" target="_blank">sudo room</a>! To top it off, it turns out PTL has the exact printer necessary for the brand-new mycelia project, based on <a href="http://github.com/labitat/labitrack" target="_blank">Labitrack</a>. As soon as the code is ready, they can be off and running with a decentralized inventory tracking system.</p>
<h2>To-Do List</h2>
<ul>
<li>Research Youtube Wikimedia Commons / WikiProject Open Access video project.</li>
<li>Follow up with about consent documents project potential.</li>
<li>Do a little probing into the wordpress project.</li>
<li>Find out more info about mycelia progress.</li>
<li>Put a bit more time in to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WikiProject:Open_Access" target="_blank">WikiProject:Open Access</a> page.</li>
<li>Post a recap and links as result of <a href="http://twitter.com/#OAI8" target="_blank">#OAI8</a>.</li>
<li>Share photos online, but where? Maybe a gallery on here?</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/geneva/" term="geneva"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wikipedia/" term="wikipedia"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wikimedia/" term="wikimedia"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/wikiproject/" term="wikiproject"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/touring/" term="touring"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trains/" term="trains"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/travel/" term="travel"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/lausanne/" term="lausanne"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/switzerland/" term="switzerland"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/fixme/" term="fixme"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/post tenebras lab/" term="post tenebras lab"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lausanne to Prague to Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/lausanne-to-prague-to-berlin.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/lausanne-to-prague-to-berlin.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-23T05:58:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Got some sleep in, not as much as I would have liked, but what can I expect having accidentally chosen ‘’the worst seat on the bus‘’ with no leg-room, haha?</p>
<p>On the other hand this bus, a new one for the agency providing me service, is more akin to an airplane in some senses. These little screens at each seat play movies, music, games, some hilarious Czech student documentaries (very odd), and six episodes of one television show: ‘’Friends‘’ ^.^ heh.</p>
<p>There was advertisement of wifi on the bus, but I was told it would only work in the Czech Republic&mdash;now that we are here, I am still waiting, with no signal from the bus… and no signal from the terminal. Hopefully bus 167 to Berlin will have wifi enabled ;).</p>
<p>Lausanne was a great time, many thanks to the folks at FixMe like Jean-Baptiste and especially Malloc, who carted me out to the countryside for a great walk through some Swiss farms and ultimately asking his girlfriend if I can crash at her house in a small village (~200 persons) outside of town. The next day he got me back to Fixme in Lausanne, we shared an excellent good fondue in the old part of town, hacked a bit on a <a href="http://ba.chgrp.org/" target="_blank">BACH</a> port of <a href="http://hackerspaces.ch" target="_blank">hackerspaces.ch</a> before I left! I hope to return, especially now knowing that the Swiss hackerspaces are learning to coordinate, starting simple through <a href="http://hackerspaces.ch/" target="_blank">hackerspaces.ch</a> (started by #fixme) as well as through a <a href="http://ccc-ch.ch/" target="_blank">CCC Switzerland</a> group. Perhaps in two years for the next #OAI8? Fixme members are more than welcome to visit the bay area&mdash;hit me up ;).</p>
<p><a href="http://hackerspaces.org/wiki/Fixme" target="_blank">Fixme</a> has an odd problem for hackerspaces. Despite being open for 3 years now and following the <a href="">hackerspace patterns</a>, the space is often closed and not used enough! They have enough full-member income to stabilize rent, even with student discounts for that tier and a second tier of membership that is cheaper. Part of the problem, they think, is that not enough folks have access. This was a bit odd to me, and upon further inquisition, it turns out a member poll they thought had attested to a lack of interest in keys was quite the opposite&mdash;people want them (glad I asked)!</p>
<p>In the meantime, they already set up a system for giving keys to folks who host events in the space, like meetups, as a way to encourage use and distribute access. Further, they are using a trust network of their membership to distribute additional keys (members get 3 keys and give 2 to people they trust). Since the keys use RFID, they can revoke access if necessary. My theory is: the ability to revoke is more useful than revoking itself. </p>
<p>So far, both PTL and Fixme are entirely men, the former has women stop by sometimes during their Tuesday dinner event, and the latter only when girlfriends of members attend (though there is one person who has been in more than a couple times). My conversations with members of both spaces indicate they think they would benefit from having different kinds of folks involved, it is just unclear how&mdash;and to me, the seeming lack of a champion. For instance, a girlfriend of one of the Fixme members drew their logo, which is a pretty cool androgynous cyborg. </p>
<p>The question is perhaps, what do folks who have already made touch points with these spaces want? How can the space be welcoming and open to their needs, interests, and beneficial additions to overall visions?</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/lausanne/" term="lausanne"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/prague/" term="prague"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/berlin/" term="berlin"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/touring/" term="touring"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/buses/" term="buses"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/travel/" term="travel"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/fixme/" term="fixme"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/post tenebras lab/" term="post tenebras lab"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/hackerspaces/" term="hackerspaces"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/rain/" term="rain"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arrival]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/arrival.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/arrival.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-19T08:24:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Geneva airport is not poorly designed, works well enough to get through from plane to train into the city. Not enough maps though, had to resort to the phone directions. </p>
<p>The mountainscape was an impressive view, I hope to take it all in later. Ah, the humidity is wonderful, overcast but muggy, what a pleasure!</p>
<p>Train tunnel graffiti is a familiar and welcome sight. More thoughts later, not sure when exactly is my stop.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/geneva/" term="geneva"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trip/" term="trip"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/travel/" term="travel"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trains/" term="trains"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop in New York, and Lift]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/stop-in-new-york-and-lift.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/stop-in-new-york-and-lift.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-18T20:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:59:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I &lt;3 New York city. Yes, in the cheesiest possible way because I do not live there and if I did I would probably complain (an East Coast sort of thing I can understand, but with which I must strain to emphathize). It is the mark of a new New Yorker that the irks and annoyances of a rub-you-the-wrong way type of town float up to the top of your head and bubble out&mdash;least-expected&mdash;at earliest invonvenience, like what has been happening with my California transplant cousin Debbie! No need to worry, the kids are good, the neighborhood is excellent, and despite all the complexities of maximal urban density, Debbie and Marc&#39;s family is doing well, and they have <em>much</em> for which to be proud. Lucas is moving out to San Francisco this fall for school, I will see them again in August&mdash;a chance to ‘’chill out‘’ ;). </p>
<p>I get on quite well with the NY humidity, despite being a desert creature used to high and dry temperatures. I love that sweating is universal and mandatory, no ifs, ands, or buts about it, we all have to stink. But more than the weather, its the hubbub and density that prevail, lucky me only around for the bustle and none of the hussle. Quick transport, heavy on the walking, low ceilings, narrow hallways, old rickety elevators, cute little everythings, function stacking, squeezing out every ounce of space&mdash;oh, efficiency never felt so good. Cities, you have a lot to learn, it should be way easier to repurpose all these ideas and all this praxis. Perhaps such is the essence of politics, and the friction of translation. </p>
<p>The trip to and fro Newark International Airport evoked a poem:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Newark Intl &larr;&rarr; Penn Station</strong></p>
<p>A wild green and rusty old feel<br>strewn among rubble, stones, and rivulets<br>pockmarks of broken windows high on old warehouses<br>marshes and an impossible density of reeds</p>
<p>prisoners hang across the tracks<br>in a barbwire yard<br>they play basketball<br>and some just move about, slowly</p>
<p>we never see this green in the citier parts<br>but damn what a number of bricks<br>they make it easy to imagine<br>the hands it took to lay</p>
<p>a woman darts across the platform at secaucus<br>just before her, a man slipped in the train<br>from his wake, she pulls the doors open<br>barely enough to squeeze in, smiling</p>
<p>on my train<br>seated commuters return home<br>it reminds me of California trains<br>San Jose<br>San Juaquin<br>but did I mention the green? and old too…</p>
</blockquote>


<p>In an earnest effort at earliness, I showed up to the terminal 3 comfortable hours before flight time. All possible crises averted, yet, as 5:00pm approached, we already hit a number of unanticipated delays. While in New York earlier in the day, I saw an SUV pull up the street, approaching me, and thinking perhaps this driver was seeking a word, I peered into their windows, and no sooner than she came to a rest did the rear passenger door open to a young girl… expressing her upset stomach on the street. I had been wondering why the girl in the front seat was giving herself such an intense face-palm. Well little did I know this would become a theme&mdash;the plane that arrived for us to go to Geneva had what was apparently a chaotic fit of human oral excrement&mdash;to a degree requiring more than their initial cleaning attempts, but an actual carpet replacement. And finally, with our flight just stablizing in air, I see a young boy with a petrified look, shirtless, speckled with his upchuck swifted by his father to a rear restroom.</p>
<p>I actually love these humanly things very much, and am happy to see so much life exposed and unfolding. We have nothing to be ashamed of, and I wish all these sick children the best&mdash;despite arriving late for my conference on Wednesday ^.^</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/new york/" term="new york"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/newark/" term="newark"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/new jersey/" term="new jersey"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/family/" term="family"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trip/" term="trip"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/travel/" term="travel"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/flight/" term="flight"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/planes/" term="planes"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On My Way to Geneva]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/on-my-way-to-geneva.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/on-my-way-to-geneva.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-17T09:12:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing this on a plane, coasting over the US toward Newark, NJ where I will stay for the evening, catching a connection to Geneva tomorrow morning. Laying it all bare here (that is right folks&mdash;all honesty!), I missed my connecting flight because I showed up (on time) to Oakland Airport (OAK) rather than San Francisco (SFO). &gt;.&lt;</p>
<p>It took me all until I reached the terminals to realize there was no United airline and /no/ flight waiting for me in Oakland. </p>
<p>Luckily, I doubled-back on BART all the way to SFO, which took about 1 hour and 45 minutes, in time to at least catch a flight out to the east coast, where I can pick an early flight in the morning to Switzerland.</p>
<p>All is well that ends well right? There was no charge and the adventure indeed has begun.</p>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/trip/" term="trip"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/geneva/" term="geneva"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/oai8/" term="oai8"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/travel/" term="travel"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/flight/" term="flight"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/planes/" term="planes"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/adventure/" term="adventure"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Launching a new blog on Pelican]]></title>
    <link href="http://existenceproof.net/launching-a-new-blog-on-pelican.html/"/>
    <id>http://existenceproof.net/launching-a-new-blog-on-pelican.html/</id>
    <published>2013-06-16T23:12:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-30T07:39:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Trying my first post :D</p>
<p><a href="http://getplican.com" target="_blank">Pelican</a> turned out to be a bit of a pain in the ass. No holds barred here, startup was fairly annoying and would probably be much harder for folks /completely/ unfamiliar with python applications.</p>
<p>I stepped into the <a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.2/getting_started.html#installing-pelican" target="_blank">quick-start walkthrough</a>, borrowed a few components from pelicanconf.py configuration files on the web, checked out available <a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes" target="_blank">pelican-themes</a>, and settled on a slight remix of <a href="http://github.com/shreeshga/just-read-theme.git" target="_blank">Just-Read</a> used on <a href="http://www.chippedprism.com/" target="_blank">chippedprism</a> (at least to start).</p>
<p>So why go through with it?</p>
<p>I have a several goals:</p>
<ol>
<li>Try to write more HTML5</li>
<li>Reap benefits &amp; low overhead of static content sites</li>
<li>Adopt a community-used tool for saving time/energy and using handy features</li>
<li>Strengthen my markdown skills</li>
<li>Leverage VIM more often for writing long-form text</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/firsts/" term="firsts"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/launch/" term="launch"/>
    <category scheme="http://existenceproof.net/tags/pelican/" term="pelican"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
